Evan Barger

epbarger@gmail.com 781-738-4175 epbarger.github.io

SUMMARY

Software developer with over three years of full time experience. Very experienced with Ruby/Rails, with additional professional experience in JavaScript (Node/React), Go, and Java. Focused primarily on back-end development, but a competent front-end developer as well. Related interests include computer security, hobbyist electronics, and video game development.

EXPERIENCE

EverQuote - Senior Software Engineer

June 2014 - Present

Senior Software Engineer, Distribution (March 2017 - Present)

- Writing new micro-services to drastically improve performance of important legacy software.
- Working in Go, Ruby, and React.

Senior Software Engineer, Life Insurance (Jan 2016 - March 2017)

- Implemented life insurance support across the company's many pieces of infrastructure.
- Led engineering decisions and helped drive life insurance marketing at EverQuote.
- Presented weekly to CEO and CTO on performance, design decisions, and A/B test results.
- Wrote Java code to power new and existing partner integrations.
- Transitioned responsibility to the main engineering team once the project grew enough.

Software Engineer, EverQuote Pro (June 2014 - Jan 2016)

- Contributed to EverQuote's business facing web application, EverQuote Pro (Rails, Node.js), as part of a team of six.
- Assisted team members with design decisions.
- Released new builds of EverQuote Pro to staging and production environments.

AdHarmonics (now EverQuote) - Engineering Intern

May 2013 - Dec 2013

Developed new features for Ruby on Rails consumer-facing lead generation platform.

nSphere/Survey.com - Software Development Intern

June 2012 - May 2013

 Helped develop and maintain a backend Ruby on Rails application that serves surveys for market research purposes.

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts, Amherst

- B.S. Computer Systems Engineering, 2014
- Relevant Courses: Software Engineering, Data Structures, System Software Design, Computer Systems Lab, Security Engineering, Trustworthy Computing (Network Security), Networks and the Internet, Statistics, Probability and Random Processes